Guide to the Beardsley Ruml Papers 1917-1960
University of Chicago Library
- Series III: Speeches and Writings
  - "Bulova Watch Co. School of Watchmaking," January 1950. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Speech at 1950 Kleinert Annual Notions Breakfast, February 7, 1950; Summary of Remarks made at Kleinert Annual Notions Breakfast. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Writings, 1944-1950, "The Aspiration for Freedom," Address before the American Association of School Administrators, February 28, 1950 "The Measure of Freedom," Press Feature, July 1950; Tufts College Commencement, July 18, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - "Struggle for Tax Reform," A Communication, March 24, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Writings, 1950, "Coming Shifts in Fiscal Policy," The New England Council, March 24, 1950 "Looking Ahead to Coming Shifts in Fiscal Policy," Des Moines Public Schools Adult Education Forum, March 27, 1950 "Coming Shifts in Fiscal Policy," New York State Bankers Association, June 17, 1950. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - "Corporate Management as a Locus of Power," Address before Third Annual Conference N.Y.U. School of Law, April 3, 1950; Address before American Bar Association, September 19, 1950; University of Oregon, March 10, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Merrill Foundation Lectures, Princeton University, May 1950, "What is the CED? How Does It Work?" May 1, 1950 "National Fiscal Policy," May 2, 1950 "International Economic Relations," May 8, 1950 "International Economic Relations," May 8, 1950 "National Security and Our Individual Freedom," May 9, 1950. (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Remarks at ILGWU Convention, May 27, 1950. (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - "The Foreseeable Economic Future," Address at Tenth Anniversary Dinner of Industrial Surveys Co., Inc., October 27, 1950. (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - "Remarks on the Excess Profits Tax," following address at The American Bar Association, Washington, D.C., September 19, 1950. Summary of Proposal made at October 19th Meeting of Businessmen's Committee on Defense Profit Taxation. (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Testimony and writings, 1950, Testimony Against the Excess profits Tax, Beardsley Ruml, December 5, 1950; Leon Henderson, November 16, 1950; Robert C. Tait, November 16, 1950. "How Should We Tax Corporate Earnings for the Defense Emergency?" NBC Broadcast "Pro and Con," December 8, 1950. (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - "Issues of Fiscal Policy in the United States," Investment Dealers' Association of Canada, Montreal, February 2, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - "Do Boards of Directors Satisfy Today's Needs?" Dun's Review, February 1951. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - "Management Under the Excess Profits Tax," 16th Annual Meeting, Gas Appliance Manufacturers Association, Chicago, April 17, 1951; 1951 Economic Conference, November 8, 1951; Reprinted Michigan Business Review, July 1951 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - "The Economics of Defense," Superior Market Institute, Chicago, May 14, 1951; Shortened Version to Retail Jewelers Association of Western Pennsylvania, Pittsburgh, June 6, 1951. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - "Taxing Corporate Profits, Policy Considerations," University of Michigan Law School, Ann Arbor, June 26, 1951. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - "Success in Spite of Excess," Dun's Review, August 1951. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - "The Five Percent," National Planning Association Pamphlet No. 73, August 1951; Five Percent Letter, November 30, 1951. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - "The Bulova Watch Company as an Example," Joseph Bulova School of Watchmaking, Woodside, N.Y., August 14, 1951. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - "Our National Need, Savings," Harper's Magazine, September 1951 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - "The Economics of Defense," Mobile, Alabama, October 23, 1951. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - "Merchandising Today and For the Future," The Wool Bureau National Press Luncheon, Los Angeles, October 30, 1951. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - "Taxation Today and Tomorrow," The Farmers and Merchants Bank Forum, Long Beach, California, November 1, 1951. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - "Business Financial Cooperation with the Liberal Colleges," Independent and Church Related Colleges of Indiana, Indianapolis, November 19, 1951; Fort Wayne, November 20, 1951. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - "Defense, Taxes and Your Business," Remarks at Manufacturing Chemists Association Banquet, Waldorf-Astoria Hotel, December 13, 1951. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - "Puerto Rico, An Example of Cooperation of Public and Private Capital," March 2, 1952. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Notes for a Lecture on Some Issues of "Choice and Duty - Do They Exist?" 1948, 1949, 1952. (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - "Testimony before Subcommittee on General Credit Control and Debt, Management of the Joint Committee on the Economic Report," March 20, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - "Memorandum on Economic Development," To the Government of Puerto Rico, Final Draft, May 5, 1952. (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - "Jewelers Acceptance Corporation, First Annual Report," May 15, 1952. (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Memorandum to Government Finance Committee, Suggestions for Committee Report, May 19, 1952. (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - "The New Defense Era," University of Louisville Commencement, June 2, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - The Manual of Corporate Giving, Chapter 2, National Planning Association; Reprinted in Connecticut Industry, February 1953; Pendennis Club Luncheon, Louisville, June 2, 1952; "Policy and Administration of a Five Percent Program" (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - "The United States of Europe, A Hope for Peace," Collier's, June 21, 1952; Reader's Digest, October 1952. (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - "Proposal for an Investment Co. in Puerto Rico," Memorandum #2 to Roberto de Jesus Toro, July 19, 1952. (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - "Taxation of Business in Puerto Rico," Memorandum to Teodoro Moscoso, July 20, 1952. (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - "Public Administration and Economic Development," Summary of Talk to Puerto Rico Chapter of American Society for Public Administration, July 29, 1952; published in ASPA Newsletter, September. (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Memorandum on Tax Impressions on Program for Puerto Rico, August 4, 1952. (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - National Retail Jewelers Association Convention, Remarks at Waldorf Astoria Hotel, August 12, 1952. (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - "Working for Peace Needs Constant Reappraisal," Herald Tribune Forum, New York City, October 21, 1952. (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Iowa State Democratic Committee, Cedar Rapids, October 28, 1952. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - "Notes on Certain Foundation Problems," Prepared for Cox Committee, 82nd Congress, December 23, 1952. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - "Financial Institutions in Puerto Rican Development," Annals of The American Academy of Political and Social Science, January 1953. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - "How Permanent is Prosperity?" Harvard Business School Association, Boston, January 19, 1953. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - "Current Issues of National Fiscal Policy," Town Hall, Biltmore Hotel, Los Angeles, March 20, 1953. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - "The Coming Crisis in Fiscal Policy," University of California at Los Angeles, March 26, 1953. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - UCLA Seminars, "Analysis of American Economy, 1951 and 1960," March 26, 1953; "Fiscal and Economic Policies in the Adjustment of 1960," March 19, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - "Out of the Barrel at Last?" Collier's Editorial, May 23, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - "A Budget Reform Program, 1953-1954,". (Box 13, Folder 9a)
  - "A Budge Reform Program" continued. (Box 13, Folder 9b)
  - "Bulova School of Watchmaking," July 24, 1953. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - "The Coming Crisis in Fiscal Policy," Workshop on Economic Education, Riverdale Country School, August 27, 1953. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - "Basics in Education," September 7, 1953. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Bulova School of Watchmaking, January 29, 1954. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - "The Economic Outlook, Taxation and Investment," National Securities and Research Corporation, Los Angeles, February 10, 1954; Seattle, February 15, 1954; Hammond, Indiana, April 6, 1954. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - "America's Stake in Foreign Trade," World Affairs Council of Philadelphia, April 9, 1954. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - "The Economic Outlook," Jewelry Magazine, June 1954. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - "Financing the Public Schools," National Citizens Commission for the Public Schools; San Francisco, March 19, 1954; Reprinted THINK, June 1954 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - "Business at Mid-Year," Jewelry Magazine, June 1954. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - "The New Economic Order," National Securities and Research Corporation, Chicago, September 20, 1954; McCleary and Company, St. Petersburg, November 9, 1954. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - "Financing Public Education in the Decade Ahead," National Citizens Commission for the Public Schools, December 1954. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - "Budget in Transition," N.P.A., 1955. (Box 14, Folder 6a)
  - "The Economic Outlook - Long Range," Los Angeles Business Outlook Conference, January 13, 1955. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Testimony for Joint Committee on the Economic Report, February 9, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - "Long Term Problems of Public School Finance," American Association of School Administrators, Cleveland, April 4, 1955. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - "Teaching Salaries Then and Now," (with Sidney G. Tickton), October 1955, Fund for the Advancement of Education Bulletin No. 1 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - "The Liberal College in Transition," National Conference on Higher Education, Chicago, March 7, 1956. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - "Federal Support for the Public Schools," University of Minnesota College of Education, Minneapolis, March 28, 1956; Atlantic City, February 18, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - "Four Essays," 1956. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - "Financing Public Education," 1956 (incomplete). (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - "Pay and the Professor," February 18, 1957. (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - "Comments on the Second Report by the President's Committee on Education Beyond the High School," 1957. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Address at Mills College Club of New York, April 23, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - "Some Observations on Current Trends in Higher Education," Cornell University, April 28, 1958. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - "Memo to a College Trustee," 1959. (Box 15, Folder 4a-4b)
  - "Memo to a College Trustee - II," Hofstra College, November 6, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - "Perpetuating Private Higher Education in America," Atlantic City, N.J., November 27, 1959. (Box 15, Folder 6)